# Hello. I'm Martin Raag.

I'm a an experienced software developer, skilled in several programming languages and public cloud platforms. My background is in designing, building and operating distributed backend systems, but am equally comfortable developing frontend web applications. Before starting my own consulting business, I built and managed the software development team at a startup.

## **Contact**

+44 (0) 20 3286 3591

mraag.xyz

martinraag

O London, UK

# **Skills**

- Python
- JavaScript
- Node.js
- Swift
- C#
- Linux
- Docker
- Amazon Web Services
- SQL

## **Education**

2007 - 2010 UNDERGRADUATE, CUM LAUDE IT SYSTEMS ADMINISTRATION

Estonian Information Technology College

# **Experience**

#### **2017 - PRESENT**

#### **SELF-EMPLOYED SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

#### LIMITING FACTOR | London, United Kingdom

Designing and developing backend systems for various clients - gathering requirements and planning a solution fitting the companies needs, balancing development velocity, reliability and efficiency demands. Examples of projects include a data processing pipeline built using Python and BigQuery, which gathered data from multiple third party sources and created future projections used daily by internal teams. Most recently developed a distributed testing system utilising Python, Docker, Packer and DynamoDB for observing the network performance of a global deployment of proxy servers, running on AWS Lambda and EC2 in multiple regions.

#### 2014 - 2017

#### **HEAD OF ENGINEERING**

#### TESTLIO | Tallinn, Estonia

Built and managed the software development team in a fast growth environment of a post Series A startup. Developing and operating a large PHP web application backed by MySQL and Redis, several smaller services implemented using Node.js, DynamoDB and React. Formed engineering teams aligned with the companies strategic goals. Implemented software engineering practices with the goal of maintaining development pace and increasing quality through the organisations growth. Developed the companies AWS cloud infrastructure to better reliability and security. We relied on multiple AWS services, including EC2, Lambda, DynamoDB, SQS, CloudFormation and CloudFront.

#### 2011 - 2014

### SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER

#### MICROSOFT | Tallinn, Estonia

Developed large distributed backend services on the Azure cloud using C# and ASP.NET, for use by Skype clients. The team was responsible for the whole process of delivering software - from design and development to deployment and day-to-day operations. Collaborated across teams to implement tools and processes for testing, integration and observability of our microservice orientated architecture.

#### 2009 - 2011

## SOFTWARE ENGINEER

#### SKYPE | Tallinn, Estonia

Worked on a distributed software testing system, evaluating the quality of the Skype client on a variety of hardware, operating systems and network conditions. Developed and operated the systems web services, test harnesses and an internal test lab. Projects included an API controlled Linux based router for emulating various network conditions, a disk imaging solution to prepare hardware for testing in real time and web applications for controlling and monitoring the system. Working mostly with Python, JavaScript, PostgreSQL, Django, Flask, Tornado and D3.js.